Jennifer Cooper

UX Researcher & Designer

jennifercooper.design	0
resume@jennifercooper.design 🗅	
+1 925 482 7312	0

Overview

I am a passionate and driven User Experience Designer whose key interests lie in engaging early-stage opportunity research and concept development. I enjoy facilitating customer engagements and leading product design, working alongside experts and team members to research new technologies and develop new products.

Design Process

I am highly experienced in **design thinking** and **lean UX** practices, and an avid practitioner of **user-centered design research** and the co-design process: bringing users, business leaders, engineers and designers together through facilitated workshops to discover the most valuable problems and deliver the best solution. I have experience and skills in the full spectrum of the **design process**: design strategy, field and lab research, user interviews, synthesis, ideation, sketch and wireframing, hi- & lo-fidelity prototyping, user testing and product developement.

Professional Career

Staff UX Designer June 2018-Present GE Digital, USA	I currently lead design for OPM (Operations Performance Management) tools, facilitating alignment across GE, responsible for research and design strategy for several business units.
Sr UX Designer 2016-June 2018 GE Digital, USA	Led concept design and development for PaaS (Platform as a Service) and APM (Asset Performance Management) tools for businesses in the industrial internet space.
UX Designer 2014-2016 GE Digital, USA	Led research, design and prototyping for future flight deck research programs, using emerging interface technologies and practices. Led customer engagements and design projects for prototype aviation enterprise products.
UX Designer 2012-2013 GE Aviation, USA	Applied UX Lean Design Processes to design operations and asset optimization tools for airlines, airports and OEMs. Drove the growth of GE Design by evangelizing design thinking techniques.
Systems Engineer 2009-2012 GE Aviation, UK	Research and development for the future of flight deck systems, emerging technologies and SPO (Single Pilot Operations). Symbology and use case specialist for onboard embedded Systems.
Systems Eng. Grad 2007-2009 GE Aviation, UK	2-year graduate program designed to accelerate leadership growth. Specialized in onboard embedded military and civil flight deck systems.

Education

Experiences and Achievements

MEng Aerospace Engineering Sheffield University, UK Master of Ceremonies @ 'Primer' 2017 & 2018 Speaker @ SXSW Eco 2016 Patents Pending and Awarded in Aviation and technology:

20180032073; 20170345318; 20170210484; 20130245860; 20160307100